<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Full Stack | venGaza</title>
    <link>https://vengaza.github.io/tag/full-stack/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://vengaza.github.io/tag/full-stack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Full Stack</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 17:35:45 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://vengaza.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Full Stack</title>
      <link>https://vengaza.github.io/tag/full-stack/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukdah</title>
      <link>https://vengaza.github.io/project/ukdah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 17:35:45 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vengaza.github.io/project/ukdah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;




  
  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://vengaza.github.io/project/ukdah/demo_hu02826cf75b135d27ab552549182d3fd3_3006296_2000x2000_fit_lanczos.gif&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://vengaza.github.io/project/ukdah/demo_hu02826cf75b135d27ab552549182d3fd3_3006296_2000x2000_fit_lanczos.gif&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;349&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

Check out the full project at my Github &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/venGaza/ukdah&#34;&gt;https://github.com/venGaza/ukdah&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction: Awards play a critical role in recognizing employee accomplishments and boosting morale within an organization but most systems are out of date or too reliant upon an extensive human resources staff. The Ukdah team aims to solve this problem by working on a database-backed, responsive website which can be used to track and deliver employee recognition awards. The website will streamline the recognition process by giving users the ability to send recognition to those that they feel are deserving, and it will also provide critical business intelligence data to users overseeing the management of their awards program. Every employee deserves to be recognized for the value he/she brings to their respective organizations while organizations deserve a simple and effective solution to accomplish this. The Ukdah employee recognition website will lead the way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User Perspective: The users of this website will be employees of larger enterprise organizations who are having trouble managing their awards recognition process. These users can be split into two groups which include basic users who are authorized to give out rewards and admin users who serve in a managerial role to oversee the awards program for their entire enterprise. Both users will first encounter an authentication process where they will have to sign into an account, or create one if they have not done so yet. Basic users will need to submit a signature image in order to complete their account sign up since the signature will need to be used for their certificates. The authentication system will also feature a forgotten password recovery process which will email users a forgotten password to the registered email address. Once logged in, a basic user will have the ability to create an award. This will require the user to enter some basic information about the employee being generated and then the system will generate the certificate and email it to the awardee in a PDF format. Basic users will be able to see all the certificates they have awarded and will be able to delete them if they change their mind. When an admin user log in, they will not have the ability to create any awards. Instead, they will be presented with various data statistics in regards to the awards such as amounts, regions, and awarders. The admin user will also have the ability to add/edit/delete both other admin users and basic users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
