<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | DJ</title>
    <link>https://vengaza.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://vengaza.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 17:27:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://vengaza.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://vengaza.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enigma</title>
      <link>https://vengaza.github.io/project/enigma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 17:27:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vengaza.github.io/project/enigma/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TreasureHunt</title>
      <link>https://vengaza.github.io/project/treasurehunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 16:08:53 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vengaza.github.io/project/treasurehunt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first foray into the world of UI/UX design and I have to say it was very rewarding. It was refreshing to to approach the project from the design perspective and experiment with various tools to create high fidelity mockups. The project was created using Adobe XD and the project link is active if you want to check it out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is nothing that ignites our inner imagination like the word treasure. Many people grow up watching, listening, and reading fantastic tales of treasure hunting expeditions which lead to unimaginable wealth or power. The real allure of these adventures tends to reside in the journey to the treasure rather than just the treasure itself. The proverbial “thrill of the hunt” keeps both treasure seekers and observers alike engaged by playing on the inquisitiveness and curiosity of human nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, In a world that has become increasingly connected through technological advances, it may sometimes feel as if there are no treasures left to discover and no more swashbuckling adventures to be had. TreasureHunt aims to defeat this notion by bringing people of all ages together to adventure once again. This application creates a significant usability problem because it must find a way to capture the magic of a treasure hunting experience and deliver it as a mobile application. The feeling of wonder and excitement is a fragile one, though, and can easily be lost to frustration with unintuitive UI elements and feelings of inability to continue exploring. We will work with diverse users and iterate based on the surveys we create to ensure our user experience is not sullied or cut short by frustration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukdah</title>
      <link>https://vengaza.github.io/project/ukdah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 17:35:45 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vengaza.github.io/project/ukdah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;




  
  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://vengaza.github.io/project/ukdah/demo_hu02826cf75b135d27ab552549182d3fd3_3006296_2000x2000_fit_lanczos.gif&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://vengaza.github.io/project/ukdah/demo_hu02826cf75b135d27ab552549182d3fd3_3006296_2000x2000_fit_lanczos.gif&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;349&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

Check out the full project at my Github &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/venGaza/ukdah&#34;&gt;https://github.com/venGaza/ukdah&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction: Awards play a critical role in recognizing employee accomplishments and boosting morale within an organization but most systems are out of date or too reliant upon an extensive human resources staff. The Ukdah team aims to solve this problem by working on a database-backed, responsive website which can be used to track and deliver employee recognition awards. The website will streamline the recognition process by giving users the ability to send recognition to those that they feel are deserving, and it will also provide critical business intelligence data to users overseeing the management of their awards program. Every employee deserves to be recognized for the value he/she brings to their respective organizations while organizations deserve a simple and effective solution to accomplish this. The Ukdah employee recognition website will lead the way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User Perspective: The users of this website will be employees of larger enterprise organizations who are having trouble managing their awards recognition process. These users can be split into two groups which include basic users who are authorized to give out rewards and admin users who serve in a managerial role to oversee the awards program for their entire enterprise. Both users will first encounter an authentication process where they will have to sign into an account, or create one if they have not done so yet. Basic users will need to submit a signature image in order to complete their account sign up since the signature will need to be used for their certificates. The authentication system will also feature a forgotten password recovery process which will email users a forgotten password to the registered email address. Once logged in, a basic user will have the ability to create an award. This will require the user to enter some basic information about the employee being generated and then the system will generate the certificate and email it to the awardee in a PDF format. Basic users will be able to see all the certificates they have awarded and will be able to delete them if they change their mind. When an admin user log in, they will not have the ability to create any awards. Instead, they will be presented with various data statistics in regards to the awards such as amounts, regions, and awarders. The admin user will also have the ability to add/edit/delete both other admin users and basic users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
